Henry Pendleton

Charleston, SC 29401 | 540-761-1806 | hhpendleton@gmail.com

Github: hank95 | henrypendleton.com

Full-Stack Software Engineer

Software engineer experienced in frontend and backend technologies. With a background in sales and finance, I bring strong analytical and communication skills. My passion to create and problem solve, matched with a knack for learning quickly, makes me a great addition to any team.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

React, Javascript, Typescript, Next.JS, Ruby on Rails, Ruby, SQL, Postgress Node.js/Express, AWS S3, Firebase.

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

Ahoy - Github | Demo

Peer-to-peer boat rental service. Airbnb but for boats.

- Utilized Rails and React to create a full-stack web application with a Postgres database.
- Leverage CRUD actions to enable users to have full control over the boats they add to the app, as well as browse listings and schedule and change bookings.
- Integrated Google Maps API, geocoding, and autocomplete to aid in search functionality.
- Created a custom React hook to encapsulate authorization and provide user state throughout the application.

Laurel Bike Shop - Github | Demo

Full Stack E-Commerce site with React front-end and Rails backend.

- Designed user authentication that allows users to remain logged in through reloads with credentials stored in session tokens.
- Employed a PostgreSQL database to store user information to persist information on the page as well as save their cart items for later logins.
- Worked with different website conventions like pagination to allow quicker load times and a better user experience.

Pub Game Finder - Github | Demo

A Yelp-like app that users can search for bars with their favorite bar game.

- Created a user-friendly web app with a React frontend, a Sinatra API, and SQLite database.
- Implemented React Router to dynamically route the website for easier search functions.
- Used the Leaflet API to add mapping functionality to display search results in a professional and easy-to-use way.

EXPERIENCE

Cape Yachts
Yacht Sales

S. Dartmouth, MA 02/2020 - 05/2021

- Outperformed sales goal, by 35% in the first year, through constant contact, enthusiasm, and determination.
- Developed and maintained relationships with clients throughout the buying process.
- Collaborated with the marketing department to organize a successful sales event targeting qualified buyers.

Water Line Systems

Head of Part Sales

N. Kingstown, RI 08/2018 - 01/2020

- Exceeded sales goal by 150% year over year through the implementation of new sales tactics.
- Created and managed the Waterline Systems website and oversaw online presence.
- Managed customer service/warranty department.

EDUCATION

Flatiron School
Full Stack Web Development, Ruby on Rails and JavaScript/React program

New York, NY 06/2021 - 09/2021

St. Lawrence University

Canton, NY

Bachelors of Art in Business and Economics

06/2018